<kungfu>
<text><b>What is Black Mesa: Source?</b></text>
<text>Black Mesa: Source is a Half-Life 2 modification determined to recreate Half-Life 1 on the Source Engine from the ground up, keeping the original as much intact as it possibly can meaning plotlines, concepts, ideas, level layouts, characters, weapons and monsters will be left the same, except with MASSIVE graphical improvements. We intend to increase polycounts on monsters, weapons, NPCs, weapons and more and put forth the Black Mesa Research Facility the way it was meant to be seen and to give players the chance to fight the battle the way it was meant to be fought. Chapters and the Facility itself will be rebuilt from the ground up with care taken to keep most of the areas the same, but with major improvements in design, architexture, and more. </text><BR>


<text><b>What are your plans concerning Barney Calhoun? </b></text>
<text>The Black Mesa: Source development team has taken it upon themselves to solve this issue early in development in order to quell the massive discussions going on in both public & private forums. The official response is as follows:</text><BR>
<text>The Black Mesa: Source development team has made their final call on the 'real' Barney Calhoun which will be in the modification. After the massive discussions in both public and private forums have gone on for some time, we as a team feel that it is time to take an official and concrete stance on this issue which will allow everyone to move on and beginning thinking as hard on other issues rather then Barney. We as a development team have decided to take the following actions:</text><BR>
<text>--The "Real" Barney Calhoun will be the same as depicted in Blue Shift; the security guard banging on the door during the opening sequence of the Tram Ride. This opening sequence is also known as Chapter 1: Black Mesa Inbound.</text><BR>
<text>--A small note will be added to Gordon's locker making reference too a beer that Barney still owes him from last nights bet. It would be written from Barney telling Gordon he'd pay him back that night.  </text><BR>


<text><b>I am a die-hard Half-Life Fan and I demand you keep it exactly the same! </b></text>
<text>Not really a question, but something that is to be addressed. We know that we cannot please everyone and there will be those people who will come back hating Black Mesa: Source because "they changed this too much" or "they didn't do enough here". We are not here to give you exactly what Half-Life 1 was, because that is already done: it's called Half-Life: Source and you can purchase that for about $10 extra. We are here to give you an experience unlike any other, to build you a facility that is both mind-blowing and drenched in environmental effect. We want to make the facility come alive with the new Source Engine capabilities because the original game deserves more then what HL: Source gave it. So if do have such a need to voice your opinion on this, feel free, but keep in mind you will most likely not get what you ask for: because this isn't Half-Life: Source; this is Black Mesa: Source. </text><BR>


<text><b>You know how it seemed that Black Mesa had huge storages of Genome Scientists & Marines? </b></text>
<text>Yes we know. There was perhaps a most of four variations for the scientists and at maximum maybe three or four for the Marines that you fight. We are aiming to create at least a dozen variations of the scientists and Marines because seeing the same man fifty times throughout the game is something we don't want to happen. In order for us to create a realistic environment, we must first take out the oppourtunity for non-realistic possibilities to occur: which in this case is seeing the same scientist die in ten different locations around the facility. A possibility which has presented itself would be the faces of the scientists may be some of our development team, creating an even greater varity of scientist faces. </text><BR>


<text><b>What are you doing about the opposing sides over the automatic weapon in the game? Will the mp5 or the m4 make it through the arguements?</b></text> 
<text>Well, this is a very tedious issue with many people: primarily because if we go with one, the other half is disappointed and if we go with the other, the first half is disappointedd and the second half is happy. We have been discussing this issue both in the private development forums and the public forums about a possibility of creating a 'choice' system where the player could choose which weapon they would want during the installation of the modification. This would please both sides, but it require far more work as the changes in models weapons and something that has been attacking us ever sincec day one of the weapons chatter: bullet sharing. The m4, as many have pointed out, carries a far larger bullet then the 9mm in the glock. This is still being discussed in the development forums and we will be releasing a public statement in the upcoming weeks. </text><BR>


<text><b>I want to help out the Black Mesa: Source team, how can I?</b> </text>
<text>Well as we a very community driven modification, we know that many people want to help out, but of course we cannot have everyone on the development team. We greatly accept volunteer work such as texturing, small models, and other such things. We also have plans to create a very strong community tie through creating the frequent 'Community Project' while will enable community members to participate in development. However we are presently seeking some positions such as a General Programmer and an AI Programmer along with a final modeller. If you wish to apply for these positions please contact either 'denzil' or 'Kalashnikov' via PM or e-mail. </text><BR>


<text><b>Will there be drivable vehicles in Black Mesa: Source? Like a tank and perhaps a Jeep? </b></text>
<text>At the present time there are plans to include modeled vehicles such as aircraft, maintainence and military vehicles, but none of which will be drivable. While we know that this may upset some fans out there wanting such freedom in the modification, we have made a very firm and solid stand on this matter as we feel that while Gordon can obviously pull a trigger on weapons he's never used before: he cannot operate a military vehicle he has most likely never ever seen before. That is our logic behind the decisions as well as the fact that Half-Life was more of one man against the elements and we feel that giving you free-reign over vehicles will be giving way to the capabilities of Source, rather then world of Black Mesa. </text><BR>


<text><b>What will I need in order to run Black Mesa: Source? Say will I need Half-Life: Source as well as Half-Life 2, or just Half-Life 2? </b></text>
<text>You will only need a working and legal copy of Half-Life 2 in order to run Black Mesa: Source. You will not require anything more then what you run Half-Life 2 with, which means you do not need to purchase Half-Life: Source. </text><BR>


<text><b>Some characters in Half-Life 2 played a pivotal role in Half-Life 1: will we be able to see those you never met? </b></text>
<text>We know that some characters like Eli Vance and Dr. Kliener are key to the Half-Life story, however Dr. Breen was completely unknown to any players and that is the mood, environment and mysterious plot which we wish to keep intact in Black Mesa: Source. Of course there will be those parts from Half-Life 2 that get linked via our modification, but your knowledge of Dr. Breen, his actions and the G-Man's role in all of this (much like our understanding) will remain clouded. There is no solid evidence backing up any theory except those that interpert his words: and even then they interpert it to what fits their theory. Eli Vance as well as Dr. Kliener can be met throughout Black Mesa: Source, but Dr. Breen will remain unseen and clouded. </text><BR>


<text><b>When will Black Mesa: Source be ready and released? I want to play it now! </b></text>
<text>At present we are holding a 'When It's Done' stance because we honestly don't know. It could take a year, it could take two years: we can promise you that when we know, we'll let you know. We ate presently estimating roughly a year to a year and a half for development. Beta testing would follow and then following that would be a release. We can promise you that the wait will be worth it: we are only trying to create the best Half-Life 1 experience ever. </text><BR>


<text><b>Are you going to include HL2 weapons and enemies?</b> </text>
<text>Yes and no. Again, this is a question which needs to be broken into two smaller questions: will you be using Half-Life 2 models in Black Mesa: Source and then will you be using the weapons themselves in Black Mesa: Source. Answer to the first question is yes: we plan to bring over the crowbar and possibly the rocket-launcher, 357 Magnum & Crossbow. Enemies that will most likely be brought over at the HeadCrab, G-Man, Barnacles, and a modified version of the Vortigaunts from Half-Life 2. Other then those, the world models (static and physics) will be incorporated where they will be useful. Are we planning to take the weapons themselves and put them into our mod: no. We have no intention of adding the gravity gun (handheld version), the H&K USP Match, et cetera. These weapons were unique to Half-Life 2 and play no role in Half-Life 1: meaning they will not be present in Black Mesa: Source. </text><BR>


<text><b>Do you need, or have you gotten, approval from VALVe to proceed with this? </b></text>
<text>At the present time we have yet to receive word back from Valve Software on any intellectual property right clarifications we have requested. Valve is quite supportive of the modification community and they even said in one of the press releases, "...a community remake is not only possible, it's invietable..." meaning that they know it will be done. That invietability becomes reality with Black Mesa: Source, taking the ground-breaking elements from Half-Life 1 and spawning a whole new generation of the Black Mesa Facility. We have yet to be contacted by any lawyers or individuals from Valve for any kind of misinterpurtations of intellectual property rights, so we await their e-mails: and hope they send us their best wishes. </text><BR>


<text><b>Man, the [weaponname] would be awesome if it had [feature], can you add it? </b></text>
<text>Use the search function on these forums to find if the weapon already has a discussion thread opened for it. If there is none, then feel free to start one. </text><BR>


<text><b>Will there be a multiplayer for Black Mesa: Source? Will there be a Co-operative Game-Style to Black Mesa: Source?  </b></text>
<text>Yes, there will be a multiplayer portion of Black Mesa: Source. Presently, the Black Mesa: Source team plan on recreating their own co-operative element to the modification, but the option of creating a map-series for the Sven Co-operative Modification is an option which has yet to be closely examined.  With respect to multiplayer action itself, officially we are planning on creating a DeathMatch and Team DeathMatch Multiplayer.  However, this may increase into Capture the Flaq as well as other interesting gamemodes.</text><BR>


<text><b>Do you intend to port the other Half-Life expansions in the source engine too? (Expansions are Opposing Force & Blue Shift) </b></text>
<text>At the present time, there are no plans to begin development of Opposing Force or Blue Shift, both Half-Life 1 expansions, any time soon. As our present project is a very ambitous one as it stands now, taking on such other expansions would be self-sacraficial (aka, way too much work). In relation to this, we do NOT intend to combine Opposing Force with Half-Life, much like it was done in Halo 2 (Master-Chief, Aliens, Master Chief, Aliens). Black Mesa: Source stands strong by its belief, as the original did, that: YOU ARE GORDON FREEMAN.</text><BR>


<text><b>Half-Life 1 was noticably linear, will maps in Black Mesa: Source include alternate routes, expanded or new rooms, et cetera?</b></text>
<text>Black Mesa: Source was founded on the premise that we were going to rebuild the Black Mesa Research Facility with a sense that everything was connected and that the player had choice. New rooms, alternative routes and actions are something which we plan to create, but not all situations can have them.</text><BR>

<text><b>Can I beta test Black Mesa: Source? </b></text>
<text>When we feel the time is right to allow others to view our work to get an independant look and response, then we will begin bringning in beta testers. Now, nothing final has been laid out for criteria for beta testing, but those active within the LeakFree and Black Mesa: Source communities are sure to be given first considerations.  Asking and begging us to be a beta tester will have yourself added to a list.  Those on the list will not be considered for beta testing status and once you are on the list: it is very, VERY hard to get off.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will there be gibbing in Black Mesa: Source? </b></text>
<text>Based upon explosions and their proximity to the entity in question, yes gibbing will be possible in BMS.</text><BR>


<text><b>Can Barneys use different weapons like the shotgun?</b></text>
<text>As the code is already implemented into Black Mesa: Source, yes Barney's will be able to have multiple weapon choices.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will Black Mesa: Source include monsters that were cut from Half Life and/or new monsters created by the Black Mesa: Source Team? </b></text>
<text>Some enemies that were cut from the original game will be included in Black Mesa: Source based on the locations as they are to be placed, as well as the consensus that they would make the experience more immersive. With this in mind, the path to expand upon the Xen lifelines, gender alterations for a second version of the same monster may be created. The Gargantua was presumed to be a male and you fight him several times; an example of such gender alterations would be creating a different skin and slightly different model for creating a feminine version of the Garg. </text><BR>


<text><b>What are the plans of the Black Mesa: Source Team concerning the Half-Life Demo: Uplink?</b></text>
<text>The Uplink demo will be recreated onto the Source engine and will be used as the demo to Black Mesa: Source, as it was the demo to Half-Life 1.  More details will come as they arrive.</text><BR>


<text><b>Mirrors, will they appear? </b></text>
<text>No.</text><BR>


<text><b>Do you plan on strengthening connections (story, character, weapon) to Half-Life 2? </b></text>
<text>The connections between Half-Life 1 and Half-Life 2 are apparent in parts in the sequel and knowing the events of the sequel, we plan to create a stronger connection of the events in which lead into Half-Life 2. While leaving many questions unanswered one was of the key factors in Half-Life 1's success, one cannot simply let the storyline stay as it was and give it stronger ties to the new game. </text><BR>


<text><b>Will female scientists appear?</b></text>
<text>Yes, female variants of scientists, technicians and POSSIBLY grunts will appear in Black Mesa: Source. The original said it best when the PA system cited "the Black Mesa Research Facility is an equal oppourtunity employer...". </text><BR>


<text><b>What are your plans concerning Dr. Issac Kleiner?</b></text>
<text>In an e-mail that surfaced some time ago, it was said that Marc Laidlaw, the writer behind the Half-Life saga, expressed his own views on who and where Dr. Kliener who and was after the incident. He said that if any one scientist was to be Kliener, it would the man with Eli after coming out of the test chamber. We too may choose to include Kliener at this moment in time, keeping true to the writers words, or not at all. Such things as storyline plots are to be finalized some time into production. </text><BR>


<text><b>Will you be taking advantage of the 3d background effects? </b></text>
<text>Yes, the scenes will be choosen based on activity, loading times and relevance to the chapter you are playing. It is not discussed whether or not there will be an option to disable 3d backgrounds and display a simple animated background like the original had. </text><BR>


<text><b>What about Dr. Eli Vance: his leg and his family? </b></text>
<text>The team has crafted an official response to the Eli issue, and it is as follows: "After a unanamious decision by the development team, you will not see Eli Vance's daughter Alex or his wife through the course of Black Mesa: Source. You will not see Eli lose his leg in Black Mesa: Source nor will you interact with him beyond the chapter following the Incident. We, the development team, stand behind this issue as it would create storyline/gameplay inconsistancies through the course of the game."</text><BR>


<text><b>Will there be a helmet or helmet window for you to look out of in Black Mesa: Source? </b></text>
<text>Even though the HEV suits you saw in Xen had helmets, you WILL NOT be looking through the square window of a helmet. THe HUD will be displayed as normal and there will be no helmet added to the suit model you pick up. </text><BR>


<text><b>Will you be using the HD weapons or the original ones in Half-Life? </b></text>
<text>Apart from the option to use the m4/mp5, the original weapons will be used. The weapons will all be remodeled based off of their original counter-parts. </text><BR>


<text><b>Will you be using High-Dynamic Range Lighting (HDR) in Black Mesa: Source? </b></text>
<text>HDR may be implemented into Black Mesa: Source, but we cannot confirm or deny it at this time.  More details will be released as time continues.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will you add a player model and a pickup animations for the hands? </b></text>
<text>No, animations for picking up objects such as boxes and other, pickups, such as health kits and ammunition will not have special animations for them.  It would require a large amount of work and just isn't in the Half-Life style to do so.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will you be creating new music?</b></text>
<text>Yes, Black Mesa: Source will feature an entirely original (however, Half-Life based) soundtrack.  </text><BR>



<text><b>Will you re-record the voice lines or simply up the quality on them? </b></text>
<text>Some lines are quite useable as is, of course with minor alterations to improve quality levels.  However, we will still be featuring custom lines and that will require us to seek talented voice artists from across the globe.</text><BR>



<text><b>Will you be including Opposing Source weaponry in Black Mesa: Source?</b></text>
<text>In the Single-Player versions, no.  Multiplayer options have yet to be discussed.</text><BR>


<text><b>Are there plans on adding more grunts, snipers, tanks etc. to the game to make it different so it isn't completetly predictable? </b></text>
<text>Of course.  The worlds will be similiar, but as has been seen with Surface Tension: you simply cannot have three grunts, one helicopter and a single-gun implacement covering a major center such as a hydro-electric facility.  With regards to the question, if you try and play through an area in the original game and then expect the enemies to be in the same place: you'll certainly be one dead goose.  Our enemy placement will make sure that you are on your toes: no matter how many times you play BMS.</text><BR>


<text><b>What will the BM:S Team do next after completing BM:S?</b></text>
<text>We honestly don't know.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will BMS be porting over to the HL2: Aftermath code when it is released? </b></text>
<text>Aspects of Aftermath have already been introduced into Black Mesa: Source.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will Black Mesa: Source use concepts that are already featured in other games ie. Halo?</b></text>
<text>As good concepts are universal throughout the industry, we may decide to steal a few good ideas from other games, novels and media in order to create a more immersive and entrenching Half-Life experience.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will Gordon have visible legs?</b></text>
<text>No.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will the g-man be re-done to more like the original. IE, different briefcase and I think slightly different colour clothes?</b></text>
<text>The G-Man model is just fine as it stands, and will simply be kept.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will sprinting appear in Black Mesa: Source?</b></text>
<text>It may or it may not.  Work has yet to begin on this feature and more details will be released as time goes on.</text><BR>


<text><b>Are you going to be using the character models from HL2 or Half life?</b></text>
<text>Some models, such as the G-Man, fit well as they have changed very little over the years (in terms of appearences) so they will be reused.  Models such as the zombies will need to be changed to better reflect to environment they were created in.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will you include a video sceen or hologram of the Tram Announcer in Black Mesa Inbound?</b></text>
<text>It presently is proposed, but not finalized at this time.</text><BR>


<text><b>Will you see a note from Breen/Rosenburg about the RC every time you look at a desk?</b></text>
<text>Quite possibly.  With the way the community has been handling the "Community Project: Notes & Papers" thus far, it could very well be possible.</text><BR>


<text><b>In the original Half-Life the player could kill the scientists in Black Mesa. I suppose that was a little morbid, but will this also feature in BM:S?</b></text>
<text>Yes, expect to be able to blow away your innocent co-workers who only lied to you about all the technology and teleportation research that went on at your place of work.</text><BR>
</kungfu>
