<kungfu>
<text>The ingenious gameplay, the for those times overwhelming graphics and the thrilling story wooed fans and critics alike. Today, a rough six and a half years later, Half-Life is still a milestone of PC history. Valve Software even ported the classic to its new engine, but the graphics were left untouched. Many younger gamers therefore did not play the first installment of the Half-Life series. Numerous aspects of the story and a big part of Half-Life 2's thrill are therefore left lost to many of its fans. This is also known to the developers of the "LeakFree Source Engine Development Community", who update Half-Life with more timely graphics. 
<b>Return of the Classic </b>
This is the motto the team labors under to completely re-tool the first chapter of Gordon Freeman's story. While there will of course be no changes to the actual content, the graphics will receive a facelift to suit today's Source engine in every way possible. The polycount of all monsters, characters, weapons and items is going to be multiplied and fitted to the level of quality of Half-Life 2. New hi-res textures are already in development. In the case of characters, weapons, or items appearing in Half-Life, the team's obviously going to go with the official models, new characters or weapons that did not appear in Half-Life will however not be introduced. The team has conciously decided against new elements in Black Mesa: Source: better weapons and driveable vehicles might increase the enjoyment in the short term, but would destroy the classical atmosphere in the long run. 
<b>Result </b>
The developers have given themselves an ambitious aim and try to reach it with great euphorism. The remake of one of the most successful games of all time is a big and daunting task. What was shown so far is however impressive and make a success appear possible. The developers can however not name a release date due to the project's scope. One, maybe two years may pass. One will merely need Half-Life 2 to play Black Mesa: Source - a purchase of Half-Life: Source won't be necessary. Who wants to show his love for HL and can spare some time can apply at the official site. Maybe you can speed the process so that we can enjoy Half-Life anew within the year.</text>
</kungfu>