<kungfu>
    	<header>01-18-06 // Unforseen Consequences</header>
	<author>Posted By: Kalashnikov</author>
	<text>Happy Birthday Black Mesa: Source! On January 1st, 2006, Black Mesa: Source turned one year old. This modification started as a community project in late 2004 and has thus grown to possibly the largest total conversion for Half-Life 2. Reflecting on 2005, we've learnt so much from our fans, Half-Life players and communities from around the globe. We would like to thank everyone for their support during the last year and hope that it continues to grow in 2006.

Alas, December and January were certainly rocky for us, but we're still here and still moving on with  development. Following web host troubles, we have finally settled into our new home complete with ample bandwidth and space for us to grow. It's great to say that we won't have bandwidth issues again, as HLGamer has handed us plentiful bandwidth limits: a steallar 100-billion gigabytes. We'd also like to thank everyone who supported us in ModDBs' 'Mods of 2005' competition. It was great to see everyone come out and voice their support for Black Mesa: Source as well as cast their votes. It makes us very proud to work on a project followed by so many. Win or lose, we thank our fans and mod-watchers. That said, the 'Mods of 2005' will be announced live over GameSurge Radio on January 28th.  For more information stop by their website. 

In administrative news, Black Mesa: Source will here-forth be known as simply 'Black Mesa'. Following our obligations for looking after Valve Software’s intellectual property & trademarks, they kindly asked if we could remove their tagline 'Source' from our in-development name. This is only a minor technicality and will not be affecting the course of development nor should anyone believe otherwise. Our website will still be at  ttp://www.blackmesasource.com as it reflects the project and the engine in which it is built upon.

Before we move on to the media, we'd also like to welcome some of the new developers on board. Joining us this time around are Talia, Atrocity and JeanPaul, all in the areas of level design. These individuals will be filling the remaining chapters requiring development on Black Mesa, and they are all very skilled and will certainly bring a new feel to their respective environments. Unfortunately we have had to wave goodbye to some long time members, Andreas and brute_force, they will be missed. On to what everyone has patiently been waiting for - the media!

First we have updates for the 'Forget About Freeman' and 'We've Got Hostiles' chapters, both with level design by Kester and 2D art by Synthesizer. 'Forget About Freeman' features some nice additions and has been adapted based on some constructive criticism received last time around. The same goes for'We've Got Hostiles', sporting a fresh look with custom textures and is now the next Black Mesa topside shot to be released. With the outdoor environments, we really want to take advantage of the power of skyboxes and displacements to make the topside seem gigantic.

Following the updates we have fresh new material for everyone! This update we have decided to release a  single shot of the 'Anomalous Materials' lobby, showing off more of the pre-disaster locations around the Black Mesa Research Facility. Level design and 2D art by the experienced Campaignjunkie, 'Anomalous Materials' has been shaping up nicely as you will see. The lobby has been designed with the Half-Life environment in mind, with some minor 'source-ifications', as the screenshot will show.

Finally, in level design, and much to everyone's delight, we have more shots of death match levels.  'Crossfire' is the second multiplayer level to hit the development stage with level design by Atrocity and 2D texture art by Aelroth. Crossfire, along with Stalkyard, has been the focus of multiplayer level design for the past two weeks. Both are looking promising and you can read up on 'Crossfire's' development in the Developer .plans forum on our website.

To give everyone some insight into further model and skinning development we have included a render of the .50 calibre Machine Gun. This is the first level of detail model and will be as the player sees it while they utilize it in-game. With sound effects already underway for this weapon of choice, this weapon will have your foes running for cover.

With that said, we are presently seeking additional prop modellers to help continue the steady stream of detail models needed for the Black Mesa environments. Texture artists and skinners are also in demand for our development cycle. If you have the time and the talent, drop a line to jobs@blackmesasource.com with your name, past experience and some examples of your most recent work.
	</text><BR>
    	<header>12-31-05 // Website Back Online!</header>
	<author>Posted By: Kalashnikov</author>
	<text>Well, this was certainly one hell of a birthday gift wasn't it!  Our old webhost locked us out, passed the files that were contained the website and then left us.  The reasons were privacy and respect, nothing more than that.  Thankfully, we now have a host who are not only very graciously hosting us and aiding us in this time, but they're also huge fans!  
	We are hosted on HLGamer.com, but we will continue to be accesible from www.blackmesasource.com and everything will be as it was.  We hope you will all head over to HLGamer.com and give them a big thanks for their help so far.  Our forums are still offline because when our old host was backing up the database, he split it into all of the tables pertained with teh sql file.  If you are knowledgable with IPB forum software and mysql databases and would like to help, we would be very happy.  You can contact Kalashnikov at jon.dominski@gmail.com .  If we cannot resolve this issue, we will need to re-launch the forums from scratch.
	Our January 1st update is being delayed due to this shift.  We hoped December would go out quietly, without issue, for us.  Unfortunetly it ended far worse.  As our forums come back online, we hope everyone will stick with us during this undesirable downtime.
	On that note, Happy New Years everyone and Happy Birthday Black Mesa: Source.
	</text><BR>
	<header>12-22-05 // "...looks like you're late..." Again</header>
	<author>Posted By: Kalashnikov</author>
	<text>As promised, here is the latter part of our December media release.  Sadly for those who thought the month of multiple updates (aka hell for BMS) was over: is isn't.  We're going to celebrate our birthday on January 1st, 2006 where media that isn't quite ready for this update will be released.  We revealed the majority of what we wanted to say in our last update, so we'll skip quickly to the focus of this update, media.
This update we are showing off a few stills from the 'Black Mesa Inbound' chapter, the opening tram ride of the original Half-Life. With level design by RabidMonkey, 2D art by hazardous! and Laz, and modeling talent from Sanada, Brodix and NetWarriorDan. Inbound has truly been a collaborative team effort. For those who remember this chapter, it was meant to present the player with a 'wow' factor, so its true meaning and value will only be realized through traveling the world itself, but trust us, the 'wow' is very much still there. We're sure many will note areas that are 'unrecognizable' to fans of the original, so we are looking for comments from the community. We greatly value your input on the direction we have taken on some chapters.
In the modeling section we have the U.S. Marine Apache, created by retardedmonkey and skinned by Spitfire. Retardedmonkey has been with us for sometime now and has already created many other vehicles, including the Marine LAV, Transport Osprey, M1A2 Abrams tank and he is presently developing the Marine HMMVW.  Spitfire has also been hard at work skinning other models such as the heavy turret and soon to be Marine Sentry.
To wrap up the visual department, we have a single in-game shot. Showing off the perception of the player in the chapter dubbed 'Office Complex'.  Crowbar in hand and headcrab on the horizon: straight from BMS 0.0.5 (alpha-5).  Also in this shot you'll notice our custom HUD already implemented and functioning.
Moving to audio, we have brought together two preview-tracks from our talented Plink. The first demo piece, dubbed 'On A Rail', can be heard via our web site and runs for almost a minute.  The second is from the chapter 'We've Got Hostiles' and runs for about ¾ of a minute.  Plink now brings the total number of completed music tracks to six, with several other tracks currently in mid-development.
In addition to all this, HLFallout.net has won an exclusive BMS screenshot of Black Mesa Inbound for being 'fast and first' with our media and news updates.  Best wishes to them and head over there to find the exclusive media shot.
Finally, we would like to thank everyone who came out and supported us on the ModDB top sites listing, the 'Mods of 2005' ModDB Golden Spanner Awards so far and those who came out to the radio interviewlast night.  A transcript will be up in the following days as well as a download to the audio file. On that final note we'll wish everyone a Merry Christmas and leave you with the media.
Cheers, Black Mesa: Source.
	</text><BR>
	    <header>12-18-05 // The Media... isn't here yet.</header>
	<author>Posted By: Kalashnikov</author>
	<text>December is shaping up to be a far busier month for us then we had first expected.  Rather than releasing one universal update, we have find ourselves releasing three.  We've been encircled by our fans, e-mails, and now the media!  In this update, we have brought together some information which hopefully many people will find quite enticing!
A few things worth mentioning are that we are still on the look out for a final level designer and a couple of talented skinners. Visit our web site for more information on these above listed positions along with contact details for applying. In internal development news, our programmer Nokia is well into development on our Alpha 5 build, which is set to be internally released on Christmas Day.  A lovely Christmas gift to the team with some nifty features.
Our 'Developer .plans' forum has also been shifted to being accessible by registered users only.  We've made the move because of the larger volume of older or obsolete screenshots emerging in developer files.  For anyone interested, RabidMonkey has done a great 'The Making Of.." report on the Surface Tension dam and its progression over the months and weeks.  This can be seen, along with over five dozen production images, in our Developer .plans forum.
For those of you who haven't grabbed a copy of Computer Gaming World (Dec 05), you can now read the three-page Black Mesa: Source article on our website, under media.  It's an excellent read, our longest article next, prestigiously placed along side other main-stream game previews, and is definitely worth a moment of your time. 
We've also been noted on HL2Online.com's 'Modulation' list.  It brings out what they feel are mods deserving some more spotlight!  Announcing a 'mod of the week' as well takes a fair amount of effort, which we are not for this week, so pop on over there and give it a read!  We wouldn't normally announce this, but we thought it was pretty neat being sent an e-mail and all.  Additionally, we've been mentioned at HLComic's "Extra's" section. Many of our team enjoys the comics produced from this lovely website, so make sure to stop over and have a look!
We also have our first radio show coming up!  And it's a lot sooner than you think.  This Wednesday, December 21st, we will be live on GameSurge Radio!  The show begins at 10PM Eastern Standard Time, so don't miss it!  Accompanying the regular slew of GSR radio hosts will be the talented RabidMonkey, a lead level designer and Lupus, the experienced modeler behind the Gargantua.  We hope you'll come out, have a listen and ask some questions to our developers. 
In conjunction with this radio show we will have our media update, as promised, released to the regular line of news websites and Half-Life communities.  Folks, it's almost here: so hold on tight!
	</text><BR>
		<header>12-10-05 // First December Media</header>
	<author>Posted By: Kalashnikov</author>
	<text>We haven't had any updates for a while, but we've still been hard at work as of late. Recent restructuring within the team has resulted in some new additions to the team's collective of talented members, and as such, I'd like to use part of this announcement to welcome the new team members aboard. Joining us are Laz, Limper and Raminator, who are adding their talents in the departments of textures and skins, modeling, and level design respectively. Already they are hard at work on new areas of development within Black Mesa: Source. If you see them around on the forums or IRC, make sure to give them a welcome!
Additionally we would like to officially announce our new forum shift. We have recently shifted to our own, IPB-based board system, complemented by our own forum skin courtesy of Kester, Orcone and DKR1138 of the development team and forum fame. A new website is also under development to meet the expanding requirements for our modification page, as well as to accent the forum skin. The existing site has been updated to include some new, custom music from our soundtrack and some new sounds, both by our talented sound artist Joel, so make sure to stop by and see some updates to what ModDB named the 'third best website' in the entire modification community last year.  You'll notice some images are no longer on our media page, this is because they no longer reflect in any way shape or form the final version.  Also, the HTML website has been taken down due to technical issues.
Following the loss of some of our developers, we are looking for some new people to fill in spots on the development team – At the moment, we are currently hiring individuals talented in the departments of level design and skinning/texture art. For more information on these positions, please have a look at the jobs section of the Black Mesa: Source website.  
We conclude this release with a screenshot! This week's media includes another Surface Tension shot, but this time, rendered with High Dynamic Range as is used in Lost Coast. Various levels from the modification are undergoing compiles with both High Dynamic and Low Dynamic range in order to determine what looks and plays the best. In the end, the player will have the option to play through Black Mesa: Source with or without HDR rendering.
Finally, if you think Black Mesa: Source is the mod you think should be 'Mod of the Year', vote for it!  You can stop by our Mod Database profile at the following address to cast your vote: http://mods.moddb.com/4384/. You'll need to be registered and logged into ModDB for your vote to count more, and sometimes at all, so please support them and create an account if you don’t have one already! Also, account or no account, please support Black Mesa: Source in the ModDB topsite listing by clicking here: 
http://forums.blackmesasource.com/index.php?showforum=91. Your vote counts once per day.  
Stay tuned, for a second media release is on its way for the end of December.
	</text><BR>
	   <header>12-06-05 // Small site changes</header>
	<author>Posted By: Section_Ei8ht</author>
	<text>What with the move of the forums and stuff we had us a little problem. Ever since I lost all the backend files to the bms site I havent been able to make any hardcoded changes (music, main nav links, etc). Now with the forum shift, we needed to change something that was hardcoded! OMAI! So I found a nifty little program called that actually produced a WORKING decompile of the bms frontend file! With that, the little things we've been meaning to change but never were able to are now changed. Main theme of the site is one of the excerpts from plink's quite kick-ass bms score, and the forum link now leads you to the right place. Also fixed a few scripting bugs, here and there. Small things average users probably wont notice.
Don't think that this little update is all that is happening for the site. There's a bug in the text display, in that its completely stretched accross. I wrote the original file in flash 7 and flash 8 wants me to use the component, not the text box, so its stretching my text for some reason. Deal with it, the new site will be up soon. The site will be completely rebuilt with a new design. Its just that now I don't have to get it done in a week. Now I can take my good 'ol time and actually make it good. Ah well, no more rant. Wait for new site and media release.
"I'm sick of following my dreams. I'm just going to ask them where they're going and hook up with them later." -Mitch Hedberg
	</text><BR>
       <header>11-09-05 // A prelude to December...</header>
	<author>Posted By: Kalashnikov</author>
	<text>With the holiday season closing in fast, the Black Mesa: Source team would like to detail a few of the happenings from around the community, team and the game itself.
Several team members will be participating in an online voice interview with #OnAir (Hosted by Gamesurge.net) , discussing topics related to the modification such as changes and the development process. Further details of this interview, including date and time will be posted closer to the interview. It's set for around the 28th of November; times will be announced when it is confirmed'
Exposure wise, Black Mesa: Source has recently made an appearance in the United States magazine, 'Computer Gaming World' and is soon to be featured at 1up.com. Included are a few of the usual screenshots, exclusive Forget about Freeman shots, and more information about the modification. This article can be found in the December edition of CGW, so make sure to pick up a copy!
The team roster has once again been updated, with a few new arrivals making their way to the team - Entity, Campaignjunkie, Hazardous and DynamikStylez - These individuals will be working in the departments of character modelling, level design, skinning and texture art respectively. Make sure to stop by the community forums and give them a welcoming shout.
Our forums will once again be updated with the addition of .plan file viewing being made available via the forum. The system on the website was difficult to update, and as such, has been replaced - And this way, you'll be able to see the updates easily. From time to time, they may possibly include exclusive, community-only media: so make sure to keep an eye on the plan files!
In addition to these updates, we're announcing the winner of the 'DVD Case' Competition in the lab forum. Everyone please stop by and congratulate DKR1138 on his fabulous abilities to create DVD art. DKR1138 will be granted access to exclusive media from the team in the future in order to create a more 'finalized' DVD cover closer to our release date. Once again, make sure to give him congratulations.
Last but of course not least, we have a media release scheduled for the near future, with some more shots that we are hoping will cater to all followers of the modification. Keep an eye on our website, and make sure to stop by our forums for the latest happenings around the team and the community.</text>
</kungfu>

